Ahmed Moh. Ahmed Ali

E: a.khalifa.dev@gmail.com | P: ahmedkhalifadev.com | L: linkedin.com/in/a-ali-khalifa | A: Riyadh, KSA

SUMMARY

Software Engineer with experience in Full-stack, Web & Mobile App development, and Machine Learning. Previously worked as a Frontend React Developer at Sustainable Star LLC. Proficient in all phases of the SDLC, with more so in Agile & Scrum, and exploring new opportunities for growth in software engineering. Open to relocation & remote work.

EDUCATION

BSc in Software Engineering, 2nd | Asia Pacific University (APU), Malaysia | January 2021 – June 2023

- Modules: Web Development, Mobile App Engineering, Artificial Intelligence, Algorithms, Data Analysis.
- **Final Year Project:** HosPal Job Searching Mobile App for people in the medical field (2:1 Honors).

WORK EXPERIENCE

Frontend Developer | Sustainable Star LLC | June 2023 - September 2023 | Riyadh, Saudi Arabia

- Built responsive & interactive web apps using **React** and **TypeScript**, alongside tools like **Slack** and **Jira**.
- Enhanced UI/UX of existing applications, both in English and Arabic, raising user satisfaction by 15%.
- Optimized app performances, reducing some load times by 20% through Redux and tools like Postman.

Information Technology (Intern) | Teczo Sdn. Bhd. | January 2022 - May 2022 | Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia

- Integrated backend services like **Firebase** and **AWS Amplify** for seamless API communication & functionality.
- Built cross-platform apps using **Dart**, **Flutter**, and **Java**, delivering both performance and responsiveness.
- Developed an **AI Chatbot** for a hospitalization app, improving patient guidance and engagement by **over 20%**.

EXTRA-CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

• **6th Place | Techstars Startup Weekend 2021 at APU -** Attended a near week-long entrepreneurship workshop, developed a pet care app concept, and placed 6th out of 12 teams in a final pitch.

RELEVANT PROJECTS

- HosPal: Job searching for medics | Flutter | Firebase Built a mobile app with Dart, Flutter, and Firebase to connect jobseekers and employers in Malaysia's medical field during the Covid-19 pandemic.
- **CLI Patient Administration System | C++** Created a system for registering hospital patients, managing a queue using a singly linked list, and handling administrative tasks.

LANGUAGES, SKILLS AND CERTIFICATES

- Languages: English (Native), Arabic (Native).
- Web Development: HTML, CSS, JSON, Bootstrap, JavaScript, TypeScript, React, Next, js, Redux, Tailwind.
- **Programming Languages & Frameworks:** Python, Flutter, Java, Kotlin, C#, C++, SQL, Node.js, .NET.
- Databases & Cloud Technologies: Firebase, AWS, MS SQL, MySQL, MS Access.
- **Certifications:** Foundation in C# (Microsoft), Responsive Web Design (freeCodeCamp.org).
- **Soft Skills:** Multicultural collaboration, Agile methodology, Team-oriented, Adaptable.